Brian Wigginton

Software Engineer

Austin, Texas brianwigginton@gmail.com bwiggs.com github.com/bwiggs linkedin.com/in/wiggintonbrian

I'm a fun, curious and empathetic Software Engineer with vast experience in different domains and technologies who values excellence in both engineering and communication. I've worked in multiple industries and environments including fast paced startups, advertising shops, and Enterprise InsureTechs. I love working on teams who are excited and passionate about learning together and solving interesting problems.

While Frontend Engineering is my strongest technical skillset, I've worked heavily across the stack and shipped backend applications and APIs for over a decade. I've managed Data and App Engineering teams, responsible for both day-to-day delivery of large objectives as well as working with other thought leaders across the organization to better understand their needs and goals. I've led engineering teams on building engineering best practices and developing mature development processes, hiring practices, (aA)gile rollouts, set architectural vision and I've been a teacher for a local JavaScript bootcamp. I've proven to myself that I'm an impact hire on any team I join.

I'm looking for an Engineering led company with a growth mindset culture, appreciation for Humans over employees, and pride in its quest for excellence in Engineering, Culture, Communication and Kindness. It's important to me that I work with others who possess a positive outlook and genuinely enjoy working with one another.

Skills

PROGRAMMING	JavaScript, Go, SQL, Ruby, HTML/CSS
FRAMEWORKS	Vue, Go Buffalo, Echo (Go), Angular, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Rails, Sinatra, GTK3
API DEVELOPMENT	GRPC, REST, OAS, API Gateway, Swagger
ORCHESTRATION	Kubernetes, Istio, GKE, Docker, Docker Compose
DATABASES	Postgres, SQLServer, MySQL
CLOUDS	Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS)
CI/CD	Github, Gitlab, Git, CircleCI, ArgoCD
OBSERVABILITY	Datadog, New Relic, Google Stackdriver, Grafana
DATA LAKE/DATA MESH	BigQuery, S3, GCS
AUTOMATED TESTING	Vitest, Selenium, Artillery, ab
AGILE	Scrum, Kanban
APPLICATIONS	JIRA, Confluence, Slack, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, 1Password, Office365
STRENGTHS FINDER	Relator, Restorative, Responsibility, Adaptability, Focus

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

runZero Austin, Texas (Remote)

Apr 2022 - Present

Senior Software Engineer with contributions across the Vue and GoLang stack.

- Goal Tracking Lead backend engineer responsible for delivering Goal tracking to our customers. Product requirements, data modeling, architecture and API design.
- Frontend Migration Heavy contributor to the Vue 3 migration from legacy server rendered pages. Added unit tests, contributed to code reviews, championed a focus on componentization and mentored fellow engineers.
- 365 Defender Integration Lead Engineer on API integration with the Microsoft Security API to bring in 365 Defender endpoints.
- Engineering Interview Process Lead the formation of the technical interview process, came up with coding exercises and rubrics used to evaluate candidates.
- Polyglot Award Winner Representing a well rounded engineer who is able to contribute at multiple levels across the stack.

Development Manager, Data Products

Applied Systems

Austin, Texas

Jul 2019 - Sep 2021

Managed 10 direct reports, responsible for weekly 1-1s, annual reviews, hiring new talent. Collaborated closely with Product Owners, QA, Architecture and DevOps teams for delivery of new features.

- Enterprise Data Lake Lead a new team towards building a customer-facing Data Lake leveraging GCP, GKE and BigQuery
- Data Warehouse Migration Managed the team working on converting a legacy SQLServer data warehouse to Google BigQuery. Increased speed from minutes to seconds.
- Applied Analytics Managed the product engineering team working on new features and integrations.

Senior Software Engineer

Applied Systems

Austin, Texas

Sep 2015 - Jul 2019

• Applied Analytics - Lead a team in rebuilding Applied Analytics using a new microservices architecture using Kubernetes, GKE, Go, GRPC, REST, API Gateway Pattern, JWTs, Datadog, Docker and ArgoCD deploying to GCP.

- Project Mobius Created a web frontend for Applied's flagship software, Epic. There were no APIs, so we had to reverse engineer a proprietary .NET API Protocol. Using Go and Angular 4.
- AL3 RLE Processor Developed custom AL3 RLE file parser using Go to scrape millions of commercial insurance policy records.
- Kraken Built a data ingestion platform using Go, Angular and Postgres. Centralized data from thousands of custom databases into a centralized data store for use by our product team.

JavaScript Instructor

General Assembly Austin, Texas Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

Instructor for a 10 week night-class of 8 junior JavaScript developers. Helped several students gain full-time engineering jobs once the class was finished!

Senior Software Engineer

Evosure Austin, Texas Nov 2014 - Sep 2015

8th hire at Evosure, a startup in the Insuretech space. We were acquired by Applied Systems in 2015.

- Full Stack Engineer Go, Postgres, Ruby, Sinatra, Angular, CircleCl and AWS.
- Industry Search API Developed an API to help users find relevant industries from SIC, NAICS, SIC-UK classification systems. Leveraged Go, Postgres, AWS. Feature was well received and rolled out to other teams at Applied as well as the core Epic Software.

Senior Software Engineer

Sportslabs Boulder, CO Dec 2012 - Aug 2014

- Campus Insiders Rewrote from PHP Silex to Ruby on Rails. Cloudfront CDN, SOLR for full-text search, HAProxy L7
 routing to let us do phased deployments.
- Team Lead for Custom CMS tool and visual redesign rollout of Campus Insiders
- Culture Squad Put together a team to work on culture impact at SL. We created brainstorming sessions and pancake
 morning for the team to relax and get to know one-another.

Technical Lead

Crispin Porter + Bogusky

Boulder, CO

Mar 2012 - Nov 2012

Lead development teams to deliver applications using a wide range of technologies.

- Lead rollout of Agile to a team of 20+ developers to deliver software. Wrote stories, estimation, story breakdowns.
 Mentored junior engineers.
- American Express, Applebees, MDC Partners

Senior Interactive Developer

Crispin Porter + Bogusky

Boulder, CO

Jul 2010 - Jul 2011

Vail Resort's EpicMix: JavaScript, HTML/CSS, C#

Freelance Web Developer

Self Employeed Fort Worth, TX

Apr 2009 - Jul 2010

- MDC Partners Wrote backend for new web experience for MDC partners. Ingest data from several sources to show MDC
 executives on a map and recent activit. CakePHP 1.2, REST API for Flash frontend
- NGMOCO: Rolando Character Creator, Promotion Management tool
- Other projects: Magento Ecommerce site, Joomla CMS implementations, Drupal implenentations.

Interactive Project Manager + Web Application Developer

Algo+Rhythm/Rassai

Fort Worth, TX

May 2008 - Jul 2009

Worked with inhouse and remote development/design team to deliver client projects.

Education

Texas Christian University BS, Computer Information Technology Aug 2004 - May 2008

Personal Projects

Cocktail Genius

Progressive Web Application to log and recommend cocktails. Over 250 cocktail recipes. Smart binary recommendation system based on Laplace Smoothing.

https://bwiggs.com/projects/cocktail-app/

Linux Stock/Crypto Screener

Stock/Crypto screener and visualizer built for the Linux desktop using GTK3, GJS and Gnome Builder https://bwiggs.com/projects/gtk-stocks/

go-nexrad

go library to parse and generate radar images from NEXRAD weather antennas. https://bwiggs.com/projects/go-nexrad/

References

"Brian is such an enthusiastic person to work with. He enjoys sharing his knowledge with others and does so with such passion and drive. I really hope to work with Brian again in the future. His fuel can feed so many people on a team and his constant smile is very positive to those around him. Brian, I wish you the best and really hope you'll keep in touch." — Billy Clark

"At SportsLabs, Brian provided a crucial senior leadership role. He was able to bring out the best in his teammates by example and instruction, by balancing pragmatic and agile programming, and by sponsoring tech talks in and outside of the company." — Scott Symmank

"Detailed and Creative. Friendly and easy to work with. Very knowledgeable with a good eye on current trends. Can't wait to work with him again." — Ryan Gibbons

"I've worked with Brian for over a year. He is very dependable, skilled and has a unquenchable thirst for learning new technologies. He will always get the job done. He has strong skills in both web project management and in web production." — Aaron Benson

Interests

CYCLING	Road, Mountain, Peloton.
COFFEE	Aeropress, Espresso, Pour-Over, Drip - it's all good!
SEC CTFS	What better way to learn new tech than to break it? Ask me about my PNG exploit.
HOMELAB	So I can play with different tech at home, oh and blinkin-lights!
READING	Science Fiction, Tech Books, ACM Magazine, Non-fiction, sometimes other stuff. Favorite Book: Hyperion
LACROSSE	My High School and Collegiate sport! Still love watching games.
TV SHOWS	Andor, Ultimate Drink Masters, Seinfeld, Arrested Development